Hello everyone and welcome to English part.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and
today we have part 7 of our
series all about giving a
presentation in English.
That's right so obviously not every
presentation is going to go perfectly
sometimes we do have some problems
and on this occasion we're going to take a
look at tech problems
and how to handle them.
That's right so you're going to learn
some great ways to discuss and to explain
technical problems.
Let's take a listen to our dialogue.
Okay so if we could dim the lights
Jonathan we can kick off with the first TV
advert. Please note that we're still
in the early days with this advert so it
might seem a bit rough around the edges.
Okay so I just need to click this in
the advert should pop up on the screen.
Hmm sorry about this, spare with me a
second. It seems to be a
problem with the projector.
Let me see. Jonathan could
be letting the hand a second.
It looks like the projector is not
recognizing the computer. Let me check the
connection a second. Well the connection
seems okay and the computer is running
normally. Hmm okay sorry guys
obviously a problem with the system.
Let's just reboot and start over. Let's
see if this resolves the issue. Right let's
try again. No still nothing Michael.
There might be a technical issue with the
projector. I think maybe the projector
has overheated. We might need to cool
it down for 10 minutes and start again.
I'll call IT support to come over right now.
Okay guys unfortunately technical problems
do crop up from time to time don't they?
But it's not a huge problem. In the
meantime while the IT guys get to
work on that I can talk a little bit
more about the advertising concept and
what we're looking to achieve
overall with this campaign.
All right so we're back and
now let's take a look at five
keywords that we've picked out
for you on language takeaway.
Okay so we have some phrasal
verbs today. The first one is to kick off.
That's right Mr. Ford started out by
saying that we can kick off the first TV
advert. So this phrasal verb to kick
off what does it mean? It means to start
something okay so to kick it off
means to start. So I can say tonight we're
kicking off the party at eight o'clock.
That's right or let's kick off this new
product with a big party. That's right
okay so the phrasal verb to kick off you've
probably also seen it in sports I think
in soccer you have the kick off which is
the same thing. That's right except it's
a noun so be careful with that one. The
kick off is the very beginning of the game.
Okay very good. In that same paragraph
towards the end we see Mr. Ford saying
okay so I just need to click this and the
ad word should pop up on the screen. Pop
right. I like this verb actually because
it makes me think of that but when
you're using a computer and you have these
little windows or these little
icons those little pictures.
When when something changes they appear
quickly and that means in computer talk it
means to pop up. That's right you
obviously maybe heard of this already you
have annoying pop-ups maybe visit a
website and all of a sudden these new
windows start to open. They're all
advertisements. Did you buy this by this by
this by this because it pop-ups but
also you can have a pop-up in a chat
window for example and in this case
we also use it as a verb it should pop up
so to pop up to appear to appear.
All right very good now obviously it didn't
work something was happening with the
projector and Mr. Ford was going through
maybe some of the problems and he
said let me check the connection a second.
Well the connection seems okay
okay connection is a very important now
especially when we're talking about
technical things like computers you can
have an internet connection this means
how you how you are able to use the
internet but in this case we're talking
about a projector which makes things
bigger and the computer and so those
things need to need to have a connection
they need to have a cord or something
that you plug into one and to the other so
that they can talk to each other. That's
right so as you notice we are using it
as a noun they need to have the
computer and the projector needs to have a
connection so you have the verb to connect
but then you have the noun a connection.
All right and let's move on to
another possible solution Mr.
Ford suggests rebooting the system.
Okay so the verb here to reboot is another
special computer word that means to
turn off and turn on again to restart so
if I say reboot that I'm using the prefix
they read which means a repetition or
to do it again. If I just say boot can I
say just I need to boot the computer I
need to boot up the computer. Okay boot up.
That's right so in this case you would
be talking about a computer that is
off and you want to turn it on so I would
say hey Marco can you boot up the
computer for me. Now about using the word
reboot or to boot up it's usually for
electronic things electric things you
wouldn't say to reboot your car or
to boot up your car. No this is for for
computer specifically electronics for
example. Oh man my iPhone just froze.
I need to reboot it. Okay very good.
All right and for our last phrasal verb for
today on language take away we have towards
the end of the dialogue towards the end.
Towards the end of the dialogue
Mr. Ford apologizes and says you know what
I'm sorry but technical problems do crop
up sometimes. Okay so this verb to crop
up means to appear or to happen
but not all the time. So unexpectedly or
occasionally. That's right so these things
do crop up sometimes it means every
once in a while this problem will happen.
So can I use this for a person if
you say oh you scared me you cropped up
on me. No creeped up on me. Creeped up very
good so we can't confuse those two
but they sound very similar. They do sound
similar but to crop up is usually a
problem or an event or a thing that
happens and it happens not very often.
Okay very good so I think we've taken a
look at a lot of words here specifically
phrasal verbs so let's review those
let's listen to our dialogue again. Okay
so if we could dim the lights Jonathan we
can kick off with the first TV advert.
Please note that we're still in the early
days with this advert so it might
seem a bit rough around the edges.
Okay so I just need to click this and
the advert should pop up on the screen.
Hmm sorry about this.
Bear with me a second.
There seems to be a problem
with the projector. Let me see.
Jonathan could you lend a hand a second?
It looks like the projector is not
recognizing the computer. Let me check the
connection a second. Well the
connection seems okay and the computer is
running normally. Hmm okay sorry
guys obviously a problem with the system.
Let's just reboot and start over. Let's
see if this resolves the issue. Right let's
try again. No still nothing Michael.
There might be a technical issue with the
projector. I think maybe the projector
has overheated. We might need to cool
it down for 10 minutes and start again.
I'll call IT support to come over right now.
Okay guys unfortunately technical problems
do crop up from time to time don't they.
But it's not a huge problem. In the
meantime while the IT guys get to
work on that I can talk a little bit
more about the advertising concept and
what we're looking to achieve
overall with this campaign.
All right we're back so now let's take a
look at some phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So this first
phrase we have is very important
especially when we're using video
or a projector in a presentation.
We say let's dim the lights. That's
right so we have the verb to dim.
So to dim something is to make it darker
but not turn it off completely. No it means
it means maybe to lower the lights.
We could actually see this on a computer
also when the screen is very very bright.
It's too bright. I need you to dim it a
little. Make it a little bit darker. Okay
so you can use this verb to dim to make
it a little bit darker or to make it
lower in intensity. That's right dim the
color dim the lights. All right very good.
Now Mr. Ford when he was talking about
the adverb he said well it's new and
it's not ready yet completely so it might
seem a bit rough around the edges. Okay
this is a very very popular phrase that
means that something is incomplete. Maybe
it's not perfect yet. It needs some work.
Okay so if maybe you're designing a
new website and it's maybe 50% done.
So you say the website is almost finished
but it's still rough around the edges.
We need to make some changes to
fix it. That's right so rough around the
edges is a phrase that is the opposite
of the word polished. Something is
polished if it's perfect and ready to go.
Okay and well when the technical
problem started Mr. Ford was apologizing
and said hey look I'm sorry and he
also used this interesting phrase. Bear
with me. Bear with me a second. Okay so
this is interesting because it's not
the animal the bear. Right right this is
different. This means you know
excuse me please be patient. I have to do
something and you have to wait. So this
is a very very polite way of asking some
people or some person to wait for you.
To tolerate yes. So both the animal bear
and to bear with me are spelled
the same way. It looks exactly like the
animal but we're not talking about the
animal. No we're asking someone to to
tolerate something that's annoying
or frustrating. So for example I'm trying
to show you a file in my computer
marker. My computer's not working.
I say please bear with me a second. I have
to reboot my computer. I actually have to
wait here. Okay very good. Now towards
the end of the dialogue when we talked
about to crop up. The second part
of that Mr. Ford said unfortunately
technical problems do crop up from
time to time. So we already discussed
cropped up. What is time to time?
From time to time. Okay think of this as a
set phrase because we said already
that you could also say sometimes.
So from time to time means every
once in a while or occasionally. So it's an
adverbial phrase. It's a way of telling
people how often something happens but in
this case it's not very common. So for
example you can say I like to go to the
movies from time to time. That's right so
maybe once or twice a month you like to
go to the movies. But what if I come to
work every day? Do I come to work from
time to time? No right. Okay so from
time to time is rarely or occasionally
not very often. Exactly. All right
very good. So now let's listen to our
dialogue one last time and
review everything we've just learned.
Okay so if we could dim the lights
Jonathan we can kick off with the first TV
advert. Please note that we're still
in the early days with this advert so it
might seem a bit rough around the edges.
Okay so I just need to click this and
the adverb should pop up on the screen.
Hmm sorry about this, spare with me a
second. There seems to be a problem
with the projector. Let me see. Jonathan
could you lend a hand a second?
It looks like the projector is not
recognizing the computer. Let me check the
connection a second. Well the
connection seems okay and the computer is
running normally. Okay sorry guys
obviously a problem with the system.
Let's just reboot and start over.
Let's see if this resolves the issue.
Right let's try again. No still nothing
Michael. There might be a technical
issue with the projector. I think
maybe the projector has overheated.
We might need to cool it down for
10 minutes and start again. I'll call IT
support to come over right now. Okay guys
unfortunately technical problems do crop
up from time to time don't they? But
it's not a huge problem. In the meantime
while the IT guys get to work on
that I can talk a little bit more about the
advertising concept and what we're looking
to achieve overall with this campaign.
All right so this was part seven of our
presentation series and actually these
types of problems occur
very very often specifically with
with the laptop and the projector
and sometimes it doesn't work it doesn't
recognize it and so this
is a nice way of handling it.
This is and we hope that these are
phrases that you can use in your daily life
as well. Maybe you're working with
your colleagues and you're having some
technical problems or if you're having
a problem and someone gives you
instructions for how to solve that problem.
Like I often get this from my
technical team. I say listen I
have a problem and they say hey
just reboot your computer and it would
be okay so these are very very common
issues that I think that you can you
can learn how to describe in English
with today's lesson. All right very
good and of course if you guys have any
questions or any doubts
about this or any of our lessons
please come to our website
englishpod.com on the lessons page you can
leave your comments and questions
and we'll see you guys next time. Bye!
(upbeat music)